<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Showcase | Alexander Kovrigin</title><link>https://alexkovrigin.me/category/showcase/</link><atom:link href="https://alexkovrigin.me/category/showcase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Showcase</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://alexkovrigin.me/media/icon_huc8b4885abde9ba4e48bac794b07e6b5d_26375_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Showcase</title><link>https://alexkovrigin.me/category/showcase/</link></image><item><title>SegmentAnything x GroundingDINO</title><link>https://alexkovrigin.me/post/grounded-dino-sam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alexkovrigin.me/post/grounded-dino-sam/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re passionate about object detection, segmentation, and cropping, we&amp;rsquo;ve got an exciting space for you on Hugging Face. Say hello to my Hugging Face space, &lt;a href="https://huggingface.co/spaces/waleko/SegmentAnythingxGroundingDINO" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SegmentAnythingxGroundingDINO&lt;/a>. In this space, we leverage the power of DINO for object detection and SAM for segmentation and cropping, creating a seamless experience for your image processing needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe
src="https://waleko-segmentanythingxgroundingdino.hf.space"
frameborder="0"
width="100%"
height="450"
>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;h3 id="the-fusion-of-dino-and-sam">The Fusion of DINO and SAM&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>At the heart of this space is the fusion of two remarkable technologies, &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.05499" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Grounding DINO&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://segment-anything.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SAM&lt;/a>, for tackling object detection and segmentation tasks. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at how these components work together:&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="grounding-dino">Grounding DINO&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Grounding DINO is a state-of-the-art method that takes object detection to a whole new level. With its advanced capabilities, it can not only identify objects in an image but also provide a deep understanding of their context and relationships.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="sam-for-segmentation">SAM for Segmentation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>SAM, or Segment Anything, is the second half of the equation. Once Grounding DINO identifies the objects in your image, SAM takes over, segmenting and cropping these objects with remarkable precision.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="my-hf-space-usage">My HF Space Usage&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Are you eager to get started with the SegmentAnythingxGroundingDINO space on Hugging Face? It&amp;rsquo;s easy! Simply navigate to the space&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://huggingface.co/spaces/waleko/SegmentAnythingxGroundingDINO" target="_blank" rel="noopener">page&lt;/a>, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find everything you need to begin your journey into the world of object detection and segmentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="acknowledgements">Acknowledgements&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Our space is inspired by the incredible work of IDEA-Research in their project, &lt;a href="https://github.com/IDEA-Research/Grounded-Segment-Anything" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Grounded-Segment-Anything&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exploring Text Similarity Techniques: A Comprehensive Guide</title><link>https://alexkovrigin.me/post/text-similarity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alexkovrigin.me/post/text-similarity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Text similarity is a fundamental concept in Natural Language Processing (NLP), with applications ranging from information retrieval to machine translation. It allows us to quantify how similar two pieces of text are, whether they are sentences, paragraphs, or entire documents. In my &lt;a href="https://github.com/waleko/Text-Similarity/blob/main/text-similarity.ipynb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jupyter notebook&lt;/a>, we embark on a journey to explore various text similarity techniques, shedding light on their strengths and weaknesses. By the end of this exploration, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a deeper understanding of the tools at your disposal for measuring text similarity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="unveiling-the-techniques">Unveiling the Techniques&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-tf-idf-term-frequency-inverse-document-frequency">1. TF-IDF (Term Frequency-Inverse Document Frequency)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>TF-IDF is a time-tested method for assessing the importance of words within a document relative to a collection of documents. It shines in scenarios where you want to compute similarity between documents based on their word frequencies. We&amp;rsquo;ll dive into the mathematics behind TF-IDF and demonstrate how it can be used to quantify text similarity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2-bleu-bilingual-evaluation-understudy">2. BLEU (Bilingual Evaluation Understudy)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Originally designed for machine translation evaluation, BLEU can also be adapted to measure the similarity between two sentences. It evaluates the overlap of n-grams (contiguous sequences of words) between reference and generated sentences. Discover how BLEU can be applied beyond its original purpose to gauge text similarity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="3-word2vec-unlocking-word-embeddings">3. Word2Vec: Unlocking Word Embeddings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Word2Vec, a popular word embedding technique, transforms words into dense vectors. But did you know you can also use it to measure sentence similarity? We&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to calculate the similarity between sentences based on the vectors of their constituent words.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="4-doc2vec-extending-word2vec-to-documents">4. Doc2Vec: Extending Word2Vec to Documents&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When you need to compare entire documents instead of just sentences, Doc2Vec comes to the rescue. It extends the Word2Vec approach to the document level, allowing you to measure the similarity between entire texts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="5-lda-latent-dirichlet-allocation">5. LDA (Latent Dirichlet Allocation)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>LDA isn&amp;rsquo;t just for topic modeling; it can also be a powerful tool for measuring text similarity based on the underlying topics within documents. We&amp;rsquo;ll guide you through the steps to apply LDA and assess document similarity through topic distributions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="6-bert-classifier-fine-tuning-for-text-similarity">6. BERT Classifier: Fine-Tuning for Text Similarity&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Enter BERT, a transformer-based model that has taken the NLP world by storm. By fine-tuning a pre-trained BERT model as a classifier, you can measure sentence similarity with impressive accuracy. We&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through the process of harnessing BERT&amp;rsquo;s power for your similarity tasks.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="7-sentence-transformers-tailored-for-sentence-similarity">7. Sentence Transformers: Tailored for Sentence Similarity&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For those seeking a specialized solution, Sentence Transformers are pre-trained models designed explicitly for encoding and measuring sentence similarity. Learn how to leverage these models effectively for your text similarity needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="your-journey-begins-here">Your Journey Begins Here&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Throughout &lt;a href="https://github.com/waleko/Text-Similarity/blob/main/text-similarity.ipynb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this notebook&lt;/a>, you&amp;rsquo;ll find code examples and explanations for each technique. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re working on a search engine, chatbot, or any NLP project, understanding text similarity is key to success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feel free to experiment with the provided code, tweak parameters, and adapt these techniques to your unique requirements. By the end of your exploration, you&amp;rsquo;ll be equipped with a versatile toolkit for tackling text similarity challenges in the ever-evolving field of NLP. Happy exploring!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>